漫漫阶梯
Stairs...
我觉得我快不行了
I don't think I can...
兄弟们 你们先行一步
Hey, guys, just start without me.
我稍后就来
I'll catch up.
舒坦
Sweet.
波澜不惊 方能心如止水
Inner peace. Inner peace.
鼻子好痒
Itchy nose.
阿嚏
Ah-choo!
终于静心了
Finally, inner peace.
又怎么了
Now, what?
天煞 老朋友
Kai, old friend.
乌龟大师
Master Oogway.
你我之争早在五百年前就结束了
Our battle ended 500 years ago.
可我已经准备好再比一场了
Well, now I'm ready for a rematch.
你准备得可真够久的 哈哈哈
Took you long enough. Ha ha ha ha...
呀啊
Yaaa!
你变强了
You've grown stronger.
五百年灵界的修炼 不是白练的
500 years in the Spirit Realm, you pick up a thing or two.
我已经夺走了这里每个大师的气
I have taken the Chi of every Master here.
- 不 - 是的
- No! - Yes.
很快你的力量也是我的了
And soon I will have your power too.
你何时才能领悟 索取越多 收获越少
When will you realize, the more you take, the less you have.
有了你的气 我终于又可以重回凡界
With your Chi, I will finally be able to return to the mortal world,
这一次 你阻止不了我了
And this time, you won't be there to stop me.
噢 阻止你从来都不是我的使命
Ah, it was never my destiny to stop you.
我已经有了一个好的人选
I have set another on that path.
那我就找到他 然后把他的气也夺走
Then I will find him, and take his Chi too.
正义就要得到伸张了
Justice, is about to be served.
《功夫熊猫3》
给我们来两份正义套餐 谢谢
We'll have two justice platters, please
- 呃 三份 - 三份 - 再要几个豆腐花
- Umm...three - Three. - And a few tofu buns.
还要一碗香辣拌面 给娇虎的 你要另外加酱料吗
Oh, the spicy noodle soup for Tigress. Did you want extra sauce with that?
她要多加酱料的
She wants it on the side
- 多加酱料 - 多加酱料
- On the side. - On the side.
神龙 你能做到
Dragon, you can do it.
- 冲吧 神龙大侠 - 保卫村庄
- Go, Dragon Warrior. - Defend the valley.
- 去呀 神龙大侠 - 保卫村庄
- Go Dragon Warrior. - Yeah, defend the valley.
啊哒
Yee-ha!
你们没摆华丽的造型 对吧
You guys aren't doing the dramatic pose, are you?
我们需要每次出场都摆个造型吗
Do we have to strike a pose every time we land?
大伙儿 永远不要低估华丽出场的威力
You guys, never underestimate the power of a dramatic entrance.
我听说某些大师只靠破门之势
I've heard about some Masters who could win a fight
就能闪瞎对手赢得战斗
just by throwing open a door
嘿呀
Shuh-sha!
华丽出场
Dramatic entrance?
师傅
Master Shifu
神龙大侠说得对
The Dragon Warrior is correct.
是吗 我只是随口 啊对 我就这个意思
Really? I was just making... yeah, I mean, yeah, I am.
双方交战先比气势 后比拳头
Before the battle of the fist comes the battle of the mind.
因此 出场就是要华丽
Hence...the dramatic entrance.
哇 好华丽的出场
Whoa, nice dramatic entrance.
- 今天是什么日子呀 - 今天将是我的最后一堂课
- What's the occasion? - Today will be my final class.
你的最后 等等 我都不知道你病了
Your final...? Wait. I didn't even know you were sick.
- 虽然你看上去是有点 - 我没病
- Although you have been looking a little... - I'm not sick.
健康 有点健康 应该说很健康
healthy. A little healthy. A lot actually.
之所以是最后一课
My final class because from now on...
是因为接下来 负责你们训练的将会是神龙大侠
your training will be in the hands of the Dragon Warrior.
什么
What?
我来教 为什么不是娇虎
Me? teach? I mean why not Tigress?
她总是喜欢吆喝别人做这个做那个
She's always telling everyone what to do.
- 闭嘴 阿宝 - 看到了吧
- Be quiet Po. - See what I mean?
娇虎不是神龙大侠 你才是
Tigress is not the Dragon Warrior. You are.
别闹了 他们可是盖世五侠 我能教他们什么呀
Come on they're the Five. What can I teach them?
学海无涯 就连师傅也是
There is always something more to learn. Even for a Master.
打个比方 我来教你另一招
For instance, let me show you another move.
华丽退场
The dramatic exit.
那是啥
What's that?
哇
Whoa!
你在开玩笑吗 这
Are you kidding me? That...what?
- 他去哪儿了 - 师傅
- Where'd he go? - Master.
他已经走啦 别那么严肃
He's gone guys. It's cool.
听从您的指点 师傅
We await your instruction, Master.
你尽管放马过来便是
All you have to lose is our respect.
说实话 能有多糟糕呢
Seriously, how bad could it be?
非常糟糕 非常非常糟糕
Very bad! Very, very bad!
好了 我们换别的招式 金猴 使出稳如泰山
Okay. Okay, let's switch it up. Monkey, Immovable Mountain Stance.
是 师傅
Yes, Master.
- 我是说 娇虎 旋风后空翻 - 是 师傅
- I mean... Tigress, Tornado back flip. - Yes, Master.
- 噢不 火 - 开火
- Oh no, fire. - Fire.
抱歉 我的错 仙鹤再飞高点 啊不 低一点
Sorry, my fault. Crane go high, I mean low.
啊 我的小钳子
Oh, my claw thingy.
呃 灵蛇和娇虎 来一招虎啸蛇盘
Uh, Viper and tigress, to... like a totem pole.
放毒 进攻
Poison, Technique.
你们俩 使出白鹤亮翅 猴子摘桃 黄马褂
You two, to... Sworming insect bite with yellow tail, Yellow jacket...
香辣 金枪鱼
Spicy...tuna.
你干的好事 阿宝
Good job, Po.
啊
Ah.
你有学到一点点东西吗
Did you at least learn a little something?
有 你不是当老师的料
Yes, that you can't teach.
还有 原来娇虎是易燃物
And tigress is flammable, turns out.
简直惨不忍睹
That was a complete disaster.
- 我真庆幸自己不是阿宝 - 他真是一无是处
- I'm glad we're not Po right now. - What a loser.
不知道师傅是怎么想的
What was Shifu thinking?
乌龟大师又是怎么想的
What was Oogway thinking?
- 我觉得被他听到了 - 我啥都没听到
- I think he heard us. - I didn't hear anything.
他说你一无是处
He said you're a loser.
对不起 乌龟
Sorry, Oogway.
- 你能不能别这样了 - 你的第一课感觉如何
- Would you stop doing that? - How was your fisrt day teaching?
- 超丢脸 - 我听说了
- Humiliating. - I heard.
谁告诉你的 是娇虎吗
Who told you? Did Tigress tell you?
金猴 仙鹤 螳螂 你爸和隔壁礼品店的周大妈
I heard from Monkey and Crane and Mantis and your dad and Mrs. Chau from the gift shop
还有刚走过的那群鸭子以及娇虎告诉我的
And those ducks who just passed and Tigress told me.
好吧 那她有没有告诉你我以后再也不会了
Yeah, well did she also tell you that it'll never happen again cause I'm done?
你是指授课 还是丢脸
Teaching, or being humiliated?
都是 我都不知道你为什么认为我能教他们呢
Both. I don't know why you ever thought I could teach that class?
我就知道你不行
Oh, I knew you couldn't.
啥 你故意的吗 为什么
What? You set me up to fail? Why?
如果你只做你力所能及的事 你就没法进步
If you only do what you can do you'll never be more than you are now.
我不想要进步了 我这样就很好
I don't wanna be more. I like who I am.
你连自己是谁都不知道
You don't even know who you are.
你说啥 我当然知道 我是神龙大侠
What do you...? Of course I do. I'm the Dragon Warrior.
那神龙大侠究竟意味着什么呢
And what exactly does that mean Dragon Warrior?
意味着 我要四处闯荡 拳打脚踢
It means...you know...just going around and punching and kicking
保卫家园什么的
Defending the valley and stuff.
拳打脚踢
Punching and kicking?
你认为这就是乌龟大师看中你的原因吗
You think that is what the great Master Oogway saw for you?
一个五百年的预言选中了你
A five hundred year prophecy full-filled
难道就是让你耍耍花拳绣腿
so you can spend your days...
满镇子乱跑跟兔子耍帅吗
Kicking butt? And running through town high-fiving bunnies?
- 不是吗 - 不是
- Yes. - No!
阿宝 乌龟与我的意见相悖 他在你身上看到了潜能
Oogway saw greatness in you, Po, against my better judgement.
比你想象的还要多
More than you can see in yourself.
有一种神功等着你去发掘
Incredible power awaits you.
这种神功强大到你无法想像
Power beyond anything you can imagine.
哇噢
Whoa!
- 这是什么神功 - 这就是气功
- What was that? - That was chi.
哇噢 气是啥
Whoa! What's chi?
世间万物流转的能量就是气
The energy that flows through all living things.
所以你的意思是 如果我当了他们的老师
So you're saying if I, so you're saying if I teach,
我就可以练成这种神功了吗
I'll be able to do cool stuff like that?
不 我是说如果你当了他们的老师后
No, I'm saying if you teach,
我就可以练成这种神功了
I'll be able to do cool stuff like that.
- 噢 - 气的运用需要自我修炼
- Oh. - Mastery of chi requires Mastery of self.
乌龟曾在一个山洞里打坐整整三十年
Oogway sat alone in a cave for thirty years
只为弄清一个问题
asking one question...
我是谁
Who am I?
如果你能安静五分钟让我说完就好了
I'm lucky if I get 5 minutes before you interrupt.
所以我现在要找个山洞呆上三十年吗
So now I have to sit alone in a cave for thirty years?
最后 当你完成授课的时候
Eventually. After you Master teaching.
授课 我根本不可能做到像你这样
Teaching? There's no way I'm ever gonna be like you.
我没让你变成我这样
I'm not trying to turn you into me.
我是让你变成你自己
I'm trying to turn you into you.
让我变成我自己 等会儿 这没道理啊
Turn me into me? Wait a second. That makes no...
加把劲 师傅 说得再玄乎一点 你就是下一个乌龟了
Almost there Shifu , just a little more confusing and you'll be the next Oogway.
噢 啊
Oh. Ah.
抱歉 乌龟大师 无意冒犯
Sorry, no offense Master Oogway I just...
我就不打扰您的安宁了
I'll let you get back to your eternal peace.
- 这是哪儿 - 呃 我哥哥的菜地
- What is this place? - Aaah...my brother's farm?
哦 那如果我踩你一脚 你会死吗
Ah. If I stepped on you, would you die?
会
Yes.
这就是凡界
The mortal realm.
你听到了吗 乌龟 我回来了
You hear that Oogway? I'm back.
天煞回来了
Kai has returned.
- 谁 - 天煞 所向披靡的天煞
- Who? - Kai. General Kai.
这片神州大地最高的统帅
Supreme warlord of all China.
没听过
I don't know.
追魂翡翠 苦难之师
The jade slayer, Master of pain.
那你至少应该听过复仇之兽吧
You may know me as the beast of vengeance.
寡妇制造者呢
Maker of widows?
好吧 我以前跟乌龟是战友
Ok, I used to work with Oogway.
哦 乌龟大师 他可是名副其实的战士
Oh, Master Oogway, he was a great warrior.
我们知道乌龟大师 又智慧又
We've heard of Master Oogway. Wise and...
好了好了 够了
Ok, ok, enough.
闭嘴
Silence!
找到乌龟的弟子 全部抓来见我
Find Oogway's students and bring them to me.
等我夺走了他们的气 乌龟
By the time I am done with them, Oogway...
这世上就没人会记得你的名字了
There will be no one left to who will even remember your name.
哈哈哈 我天煞来了
Ha ha ha! Kai is coming!
我准备好了
I am ready...
- 来教训你了 - 教训我
- to teach you a lesson. - Teach me?
- 哦不 是神龙大师 - 妈呀他太帅了
- Oh no, it's the Dragon teacher. - Yeah he's so handsome.
多谢夸奖
Thank you for the compliment.
不 绕我一命吧
No, please don't teach me to death.
阿宝
Po?
嗨 老爸 你好吗
Oh, hey dad. What's up?
我只是 回家泡个澡而已
I like just...stopping by for a little soak.
- 说吧 出什么事啦 - 没事
- Okay, What's wrong? - Nothing.
没事 我回家发现你在这跟你的娃娃鸳鸯戏水
Nothing? I come home to find you taking a bath with your dolls...
- 是人偶 - 而且加的不是浴盐
- Action figures. - And instead of adding bath-salt to the water.
- 反而加了四川辣椒面 - 啥 四川辣椒面
- You just added szechuan peppercorns. - Szechuan, what?
噢 噢 我白嫩的小屁股
Oh, oh, oh...my tenders.
好啦 我是有心事
Okay, yes, something's wrong.
乖儿子 告诉爸爸发生了什么事
There, there, son , you tell your daddy all about it.
胳膊抬起来
Lift your arm.
师傅说我还不知道神龙大侠的意义
Shifu says I don't know what it means to be the Dragon Warrior.
现在我居然还要当老师了
And now I have to be a teacher?
我以为我找到了自我
I thought I finally knew who I was.
可如果我不是神龙大侠 那么我又是谁呢
If I'm not the dragon Warrior, then who am I?
老师 教人功夫吗
A teacher? Teaching kung fu?
阿宝 这可是份美差啊 还犹豫啥 儿子
Po, that's a promotion. Take the job, son.
等有一天 你掌管了翡翠宫
And someday, when you're in charge of the whole Jade palace,
我就可以在大厅里卖面条了 哟呼
I can sell noodles in the lobby. Yoohoo.
你怎么还在这泡澡 跟个娃娃似的
Why are you still here taking a bath like a baby?
起来 起来 赶紧去干活
Get out. Get up. Go, go, go.
我们的店面就要扩张啦
Franchise expansion awaits us!
那神龙大侠模仿大赛怎么办
What about the Dragon Warrior look alike contest?
- 反正周大妈每次都赢 - 接招吧
- Mrs. Chau always wins that. - Skadoosh.
那神龙大侠吃包子大赛呢
And the Dragon Warrior dumpling eating contest?
我要保持我的不败记录
I have to defend my title.
没有人能打破你吃包子的记录
No one's gonna beat your dumpling eating record.
有人要打破你吃包子的记录啦
Someone's about to beat your dumpling eating record.
加油 加油
Go. Go. Go.
- 谁在吃我的包子 - 账算在谁头上
- Who's eating my dumplings? - And who's paying for them?
一百零一 一百零二
101, 102.
一百零三
103.
耶
Yeah!
新纪录吗
Is that a new record?
你是谁
Who are you?
- 我是李山 - 什么
- I'm Li Shan - What?
我叫李山
I'm Li shan.
我在找我儿子
I'm looking for my son.
- 你儿子不见了 - 是啊 多年以前丢的
- You lost your son? - Yes, many years ago.
- 我也跟我爸爸失散了 - 真抱歉
- I lost my father. - Very sorry.
谢谢你
Thank you.
好吧 祝你好运
Well , good luck to you.
你也是 希望你能找到你儿子
You too. I hope you find your son.
我也希望你能找到你爸爸
And I hope you find your father.
- 儿子 - 哈
- Son? - Huh?
我的天啊 真是你
Oh my gosh, it is you.
别傻站着呀 快给你老爸一个拥抱
Well, don't just stand there! Give your old man a hug!
不敢相信你还活着
I can't believe you're alive.
- 耶 - 耶
- Yeah! - Yeah!
我以为我永远地失去你了 小莲花
I thought I'd lost you forever, Little Lotus.
好吧 这下有点尴尬了
Oh, Okay. This is very embarrassing,
我想你认错儿子了 我不叫莲花 我叫阿宝
but I think you've got me confused with a panda named Lotus. My name is Po.
啊对了 你也许
Oh right, you wouldn't... Okay.
这么说吧 小莲花是你的乳名
See, Little Lotus was the name you were given at birth.
- 真的吗 - 真的
- Really? - Really.
难以置信 这么多年了终于找到你了
I can't believe it. After all these years and you're really here?
这简直太神奇了
This is amazing.
老爸 这位是
Oh, Dad. Come say hi to...
呃 我不知道应该怎么称呼你
Um. I don't know...I don't know what I'm supposed to call you.
他刚才说他叫李山
I'm pretty sure he said his name is Li.
你 来抱抱
You...come here
太谢谢你了 把我的儿子照顾得那么好
Thank you, thank you for taking such good care of my son.
你的儿子 先等等
Your son? Now hold on just a minute.
我们怎么知道这个人跟你有没有联系
How do we know this stranger is even related to you?
你看啊 一看肚子就知道是自家人
Look at that. Our bellies could be brothers.
嘿儿子 我来教你怎么拱肚子 来 拱肚子
Hey son, let me teach you how to Belly Gong. All right, belly gong.
太酷炫了 它们震动的频率还一致
That's so cool. They jiggle the same.
好像在照镜子一样
It's like looking in a fat mirror.
真想不到 我们还能一起合影
I can't believe we're taking a picture together.
我还是不明白 我以为阿宝是最后一只熊猫了
But I still don't understand. I thought Po was the only panda left.
- 不 还有一大群呢 - 在哪
- No, there's a whole bunch of us. - Where?
- 就在山里的神秘熊猫村里 - 神秘熊猫
- Here, a secret panda village in the mountains. - A secret panda...
哇噢
Whoa.
可是你是怎么知道我在这的
But how did you know where I was?
我收到的消息指引我来的
I received a message that led me here.
如果没人找得到你 你是怎么收到消息的
How could you receive a message if no one could find you?
太可疑了
Sounds suspicious to me.
不 等等 这是一则来自宇宙的消息
No, wait, wait. It was a message from the universe.
- 哦哦哦哦 - 哇噢
- Ooooooh! - Whoa!
- 哇噢 - 扯淡
- Whoa. - Rats.
现在说说 神龙大侠是怎么一回事啊
Now, what's all this about a Dragon Warrior?
你怎么知道我就是神龙大侠 是宇宙告诉你的吗
How'd you know I was the Dragon Warrior? Did the universe tell you that, too?
海报上写着呢 还有礼品店 我买了一个小杯杯
No, the poster did, and the gift shop. I bought a tiny cup.
哦 对 当然了
Oh right, of course...
你得看看 你不知道我有多少东西要给你看
You gotta...you have no idea there's so much to show you.
你会为我自豪的
You're gonna be so awesomely proud!
来呀 来呀
Come on! Come on!
我已经很为你自豪了
I'm already awesomely proud.
- 还有几级就到了 - 噢
- Oh. Couple more steps. - Oh.
我感觉脂肪在燃烧
Feeling the burn.
你也有熊猫哮喘综合征吗 我们是不是家族遗传啊
Do you have panda asthma, too? Does that run in the family?
爸 你肯定会爱上这儿的
Dad, you're gonna love this.
这里有最炫酷的东西
It's like the coolest thing ever.
这就是英雄之殿
This is the hall of heroes.
收藏了武林中所有的奇珍异宝
Home of the most priceless kung fu artifacts in all of China.
哇噢 这儿真是
Whoa. This place is...
太棒了 你准备这样说对吧
Awesome? You were going...you were going to say awesome, right?
- 因为真是太棒啦 - 太棒啦
- Because it totally is! - Totally!
不过你要超级小心 这里都是些易碎品
But be super careful, everything is very fragile here.
比如说这个装着武士耳语的灵坛
Like the Urn of Whispering warriors.
就有人打碎过
Someone broke that once.
- 谁 - 某个傻子
- Who? - Some idiot.
哇噢
Wow!
这是飞天犀牛大师的战甲
This is Master flying Rhino's battle armor.
我很好奇我能不能塞进去
I wonder if I could fit in that.
你是我肚子里的蛔虫吗 老爸 我跟你想的一样
Get out of my head, dad. I've wondered the same thing.
想知道我穿不穿得下
If I could fit in it?
你穿不穿得下 不 是我穿不穿得下
If you could? No, if I could fit in it.
老爸 过来看看这个
Dad, check it out.
公羊大师的十字弩 破过无数道城门
Master Ram's crossbow. The infinite gates smasher.
老爸 再来看看这个
Dad, look at this.
老鼠大师军团的兜鍪 真的很小
The battle helmets of Master Rat's army. They're so tiny.
海豚大师的防水盔甲 这是我的最爱
Master Dolphin's water proof armor. This is my favorite.
看 这是传说中的雄鹰大帝的战车
Check it out. It's the legendary battle rickshaw of emperor Hawk
车很拉风
Sweet ride.
爸 你在做什么 任何东西都是禁止触摸的
Dad, what are you doing? We're not supposed to touch anything.
抱歉 我应该要放回原处吗
Sorry, sorry. Should I put it back?
对 你应该要放回去 不过你这样帅呆了
Yeah, you probably should. You look so cool, though.
感觉如何 紧身不 里面有犀牛的味道吗
How does it feel? Do the hinges hinge? Does it smell like rhino?
有觉得自己坚不可摧吗
Does it feel like you're impenetrable?
有觉得自己能够以一敌千
Does it feel like you can take on a thousand warriors
却毫发无损吗
and emerge unscathed?
对 感觉很酷
Yes, it's pretty cool.
这有什么用 拉拉试试
What this does? I should pull it.
我激动到尿了
I think I just peed a little.
还有什么好玩的可以试试吗 儿子
Anything else we should try in here, son?
进攻
Charge!
快点 快点 再快点
Faster, faster, faster!
- 拇指大战 - 援军来了
- Thumb war! - Reinforcements!
太好玩了
This is so much fun...
- 开始转了 - 太棒了
- Here we go. - Awesome!
- 吐吧吐吧 - 我没事 没事
- There, there - I'm fine, I'm fine.
吐出来就没事了
There you go.
海豚穿心剑
Dolphin style attack!
- 命中 - 海豚大挪移
- You got me. - Dolphin style retreat!
准备好了 儿子
Go long son.
我还没准备好呢
I wasn't ready.
- 接好了 - 接住了
- Coming back at you. - I got it.
- 往上抛 - 来了 接好了
- Throw it high! - Here you go. Yeah, come on.
- 我要来了 - 那就来吧 犀牛大师
- I'm coming for you. - Bring it on Master Rhino.
我来了
Here I come!
我要追上你了 追上你
I'm gonna get you. I'm gonna get you.
追上你
I'm gonna get you.
停停停
Shh, stop.
谁会追上你 谁追上你了
Who's gonna get you? Who's gonna get you?
- 犀牛大师 - 怎么 怎么了
- Master Rhino. - Why, what's wrong?
你们好
Hello.
大伙 你们永远也猜不到他是谁
Guys guys, you're never gonna guess who just showed up.
不会一辈子也猜不到
Not in a million years.
只是你们不可能 你们猜猜
You can't...you just try.
- 你爸爸 - 你爸爸
- Your father! - Your father!
怎么都一猜就中
Wow, how did you just guess that?
好吧 当然会猜到 我们看起来简直一模一样
Oh, wait a second. Yeah of course. We look exactly the same.
老爸 跟我朋友打声招呼吧
Dad. Say hi to my friends,
这是螳螂 娇虎 金猴 仙鹤 还有灵蛇
Mantis, Tigress, Monkey, Crane, and Viper.
- 你是灵蛇 对吗 - 我是金猴 大叔
- Oh, Viper, was it? - Monkey, sir.
他们是我最好的朋友
They're kind of my best friends.
这 这位是师傅 他是个传奇
And this...this is Master Shifu. Legend.
很荣幸见到你 熊猫大师
It is an honor to meet you, Master Panda.
或许你爸爸愿意随我们一起到练功房
Perhaps your father would care to join us in the training hall?
您儿子要给他们上课
Your son will be teaching the class.
他肯定很累 你一定很累
I'm sure he's tired. I'm sure you're tired.
他累了 我带他去菊花房休息
He's tired. I'm gonna show him the chrysanthemums suite.
什么 累 不 一点也不累 我很想看你教课
What? Tired? No, I'm fine. I would love to watch you teach.
相信我 看我教课一点也不好玩
Trust me. It would be more fun to watch me...
- 战斗 - 那是什么
- Fight! - What is that?
村子被人攻击了
The valley is under attack.
- 儿子 被攻击 - 这太棒了
- Son? Under attack? - This is perfect!
这下你就要见识神龙大侠的厉害了
Now you can see what being the dragon warrior is all about.
跟我来
Follow me!
你们这群恶徒 准备
Enemies of justice. Prepare for...
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
痛
Ow!
这些绿家伙是什么玩意儿
What's the deal with the green guys?
- 某种翡翠僵尸 - 翡翠僵尸
- Some kind of jade zombies. - Jade zombies?
- 翡尸 就是这个 - 翡尸 就是这个
- Jombies, Jinx. - Jombies, Jinx.
小莲花 小心点
Lotus, be careful!
爸 没事 这事我每天都在做
It's Okay, Dad. I do this everyday...!
我认识他们 他们是双獾大师
I recognize this guys. The Master Badger twins.
和他们的双击绝招
With their crushing double gong technique.
对 就是这个 那个是 不是吧
Yeah, that's the one. That guys is... no
豪猪大师
Master Porcupine.
他不是几百年前就去世了吗
I thought he died hundred years ago?
全是传奇人物
These guys are legends.
来张速写
Get a quick sketch of us.
画好了吗 画好了吗
Did you get it? Did you get it?
我眨眼了 能再画一张吗
I blinked. Can we get another one?
我要被豪猪大师掐死了 简直太帅了
I'm being choked by Master Porcupine. This is so cool.
- 看 是你 - 阿宝 专心点
- Look. It's you. - Po, focus!
宇宙消息 那我再来给你条宇宙消息吧
Message from the universe. I'll give you one message from the universe...
离我儿子远点
Stay away from my son.
抱歉 爸 稍后我会清干净
Sorry dad. I'll clean it up later.
小心点 别用我的好锅 用这个
Whoa, whoa, not my good pan. Take this one.
小莲花 小心
Lotus, watch out!
老爸 看我的无敌连环包
Dad, check out my dumplings of doom.
抓到了
Gotcha!
我看见你们了
I see you.
你们的气很快就是我的了
Your chi will soon be mine.
- 他在跟我说话吗 - 哪个 他们三个都在说话
- Is he talking to me? - Which one? They're all talking.
对 太恐怖了
You're right. That's so scary.
我们应该也要试试看 说不定能反过来吓唬他们
We should try that, too. Maybe it'd be scary back at them.
好 不过我们得先商量好应该怎么说
Okay, but we gotta plan what we're gonna say first,
要不然的话 那就不是可怕了 而是蠢了
otherwise it won't be scary, it'll be just stupid.
不是他们在说话 白痴
It's not them talking, you idiots!
是我在通过他们说话 我是天煞
It's me talking through them, Kai!
- 谁 - 好好 够了
- Who? - Okay, okay, enough.
- 看到了吗 看到了吗 - 发生了什么
- Did you see that? Did you see? - What just happened?
那些绿烟就咻的一下 又咻地消失了
The green smoke just poof...and then poof.
师傅 那是什么
Shifu, what wast that?
天煞 天煞 天煞 是谁呢
Kai? Kai? Kai?
不知道 没听过
Nope. Never heard of him.
天煞 天煞 在哪里
Kai... Kai... Where is it?
这里太多装满智慧的卷轴了 什么都找不到
There's so much wisdom in here, I can't find anything.
找到了
Yes!
看好了
Behold.
所有答案都将在这里找到
All the answers will be found within.
什么 一片空白
What? It's blank?
是在耍我吗 又来这套
Are you kidding me? Not again.
等等 等一下 抱歉 好了 我们开始吧
Wait, wait. Hold on. Sorry, okay, here we go.
是乌龟亲手写的
It is written in Oogway's hand.
- 很久以前 我有一个兄弟 - 乌龟竟然有兄弟
- Long ago, I had a brother. - Oogway had a brother?
战友 是战友 抱歉
In arms. In arms, sorry.
他写的是兄弟般的战友
He says brother in arms.
你就不能一次都展开吗
Can't you just unroll it all at once?
我曾是一名雄心勃勃的年轻战士 带领一支伟大的军队
I was an ambitious young warrior leading a great army.
与我并肩作战的就是天煞
And fighting by my side was Kai.
我最亲密的朋友
My closest friend.
有一天 我们遭到了埋伏 我身负重伤
One day we were ambushed. I was badly wounded.
我的朋友背着我日以继夜地寻求帮助
My friend carried me for days looking for help.
最后我们来到一个高山上的神秘村庄
Until we came to a secret village, high in the mountains.
古老的疗伤圣地
An ancient place of healing.
全村都是熊猫
A village of pandas.
- 熊猫 - 对 熊猫
- Pandas? - Yes, pandas.
熊猫他们用气功治好了我
Pandas who used the power of chi to heal me.
他们还教会我如何释放气
They taught me how to give chi.
但天煞想独占所有气
But Kai, wanted the power all to himself.
他发现气既能被给予 也能被夺走
He saw that what could be given could also be taken.
我必须阻止他
I had to stop him.
我们打得山摇地动
Our battle shook the Earth.
最终 我将他打入灵界
Until, finally, I banished Kai to the Spirit Realm.
若他重返人间
Should he ever return to the mortal realm,
唯有真正的气功大师才能阻止他
he can only be stopped by a true Master of chi.
真正的气功大师 比如你
True Master of chi? Like you.
我 我只能发功让花盛开而已
Me? I can barely make a flower bloom!
我至少还要在山洞里修炼三十年
I'd need at least thirty more years, and a cave.
我们需要一个气功大师
We need a chi Master.
他会继续夺走别的大师的气 世上就再也没气了
He will continue stealing the chi of Masters until he has consumed it all.
我们必须想办法阻止他
We have to make a way to stop him.
败下的大师越多 他得到的气也就越多
He gets more more powerful with every Master he defeats.
我们没别的选择 只能去战斗
There is no choice. We fight.
我可以教你 儿子
I can teach you, son.
- 你可以教我 - 当然 我是只熊猫
- You can do this? - Of course, I'm a panda.
这肯定是宇宙让你来的原因
That must be why the universe sent you here.
好 那我要做什么
Okay, so what do I have to do?
- 你要跟我回家 - 什么
- You have to come home with me. - What?
- 回到神秘村庄 - 对 儿子
- To the secret village? - Yes, son.
你必须重新学会如何做一只熊猫
You must rediscover what it is to be a panda.
你要学会如何像熊猫那样生活 像熊猫那样睡觉
You have to learn how to live like a panda. Sleep like a panda.
像熊猫那样吃东西
Eat like a panda.
103个包子 还没够我塞牙缝呢
Those 103 dumplings? I was just warming up.
我一直认为 我吃东西的潜力还没全部挖掘出来
I've always felt like I wasn't eating up to my full potential.
你不能把我们家阿宝带走 不不 我要别的意见
You can't take Po away from me. No, no I want a second opinion.
师傅 再开一卷吧
Shifu, open another scroll or something.
- 我觉得他应该去 - 好 再来个意见
- I think he should go. - Fine. A third opinion.
金猴 灵蛇 娇虎
Monkey? Viper? Tigress?
老爸 你也听到师傅说的和乌龟写的
Dad, you heard what Shifu said, Oogway said.
只有真正的气功大师才能阻止天煞
This guy can only be stopped by a Master of chi.
而我只有知道我究竟是谁才能学会用气
And I can only master chi by knowing who I really am.
我 我是熊猫
Well, I'm a panda.
我去给你准备路上的午餐
I'll pack your lunch for the road.
你真的认为阿宝能及时学会气功吗
Do you really think Po can master chi in time?
我的想法并不重要
Doesn't matter what I think.
- 宇宙怎么想才是最重要的 - 所以答案是不会
- It only matters what the universe thinks. - So, that's a "No"?
- 师傅 我们要做什么 - 你去查明天煞的下落
- Master, what are we going to do? - You are going to find out where Kai is.
寻着那些翡翠僵尸的踪迹 但千万别跟他打起来
Follow the trail of those jade creatures but do not engage.
因为天煞会越战越强
For with every foe he faces Kai becomes stronger.
为什么选我 是因为我多嘴吗
Why me? Is it because I asked.
不是 因为你能飞
No, it is because you can fly.
- 去吧 - 早知道就闭上你的鸟嘴了
- Go! - Should have kept your beak shut.
- 带上螳螂 - 什么 因为我插嘴
- And take Mantis. - What? Oh man, is it because I...?
对
Yes.
吃点东西吗
Oh, lunch break?
你不用同样问题问两遍
You don't need to ask me twice.
- 老爸 - 干嘛
- Dad? - Yes?
- 老爸 - 啥
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
你说我在干什么 我背疼死了
What am I doing? Getting a backache.
你非得在每块石头上踩着走吗
Did you have to step on every rock?
- 不 我是说你怎么在这 - 那你说我该怎么办
- No, I mean why are you here? - What was I supposed to do?
如果你不喜欢吃那些熊猫的东西怎么办
What if the pandas don't have food you like?
你饿着肚子的话 怎么去拯救世界呀
You're never gonna be able to save the world on an empty stomach.
我觉得我跟着你攸关成败
I consider my presence mission critical.
关于这点 我们不能告诉外人村庄的位置
Oh yes about that. We can't share the location of the village with others.
- 所以 - 你认为我守不住秘密 是吧
- So... - Well, you think I can't keep a secret, huh?
我养了阿宝二十年才告诉他 他不是我亲生的
I raised Po for 20 years before I finally told him he was adopted.
- 真的吗 - 真的
- Seriously? - Yeah.
好吧 我想 让你飞回去是有点残忍
Okay, I guess it would be cruel to make you fly back.
- 你竟然会飞 - 鹅也是鸟好吗 阿宝
- You can fly? - I'm a bird, Po.
我们到了
We're here.
看上去还要很长一段路
Sure looks like a long ways up there.
我儿子最讨厌爬阶梯了 我们还是回家吧
And my son hates stairs. So, let's go home.
我们可是熊猫 我们才不爬阶梯
We're pandas. We don't do stairs.
我一辈子都在等着这句话
I've waited my whole life to hear those words.
扯淡
Rats.
这就是神秘熊猫村 难怪你们要保密
This is the secret panda village? No wonder you keep it a secret.
如果我住在这 我也不好意思告诉别人
If I lived here, I wouldn't tell anyone either.
现在你可以"哇"了
Now you can whoa.
李山 大家注意 李山回来了
Li? Everyone, Li is back.
- 回来了两个人 - 他找到儿子了
- They're both back. - He found his son.
- 他做到了 - 他们回来了
- He made it. - They're back.
- 李山 - 他找到他儿子了
- Li? - He found his son.
大家 李山回来了
Everyone, Li is back.
等等 我们来了
Hang on, we're coming.
他做到了
He made it.
- 他成功了 - 为什么我们要跑
- He made it! - Why are we running?
- 他做到了 - 李山回来了
- He made it. - Li shan is back.
大家都围过来吧 这是我儿子
Everyone, everyone gather around. This is my son.
- 你们好 - 真可爱
- Hello. Hi. - Cute.
- 三胞胎 - 嗨 我是酷酷
- Triplets! - Hi, I'm Ku Ku.
- 我是萌萌 - 我是帅帅 他闻起来像饼干
- I'm Meng Meng. - I'm Shuai Shuai, he smells like cookies.
- 他好帅啊 跟他老爸一样帅 - 谢谢夸奖
- He's so handsome. Just like his father. - Thank you.
儿子 他们是你的表哥 点点和心心
Son, these are your cousins. Dim and Sum.
- 我竟然有表哥 - 欢迎 - 欢迎
- I have cousins. - Welcome. - Welcome.
- 串在一起的包子 - 我们叫它小吃项链
- Buns on a string. - We call it a snacklace.
没错
That's right.
我们会再给你做一条
We'll make you another one.
是你啊
It's you.
- 很高兴见到你 嗨 - 其实我不认识你
- So, that's nice to see you. Hi. - I don't know who you are.
花娃娃 好漂亮啊
Stripey baby, So beautiful.
小心点 那是我的人偶
Okay, careful with that. That's my action figure.
能送我吗
Can I keep her?
- 不 - 行吗
- Noooo... - Can I?
没 问题 当然没问题 我带来就是要送给你的
No...problem. Of course, yeah that's why I brought her.
- 好好照顾她 - 肯定会 花娃娃
- Take good care of her. - Yes, stripey baby.
你看起来就像婴儿版的我
You look just like me but a baby.
你就像老年版的我 你就是胖点的我
You're like me but old. You're like me but fatter.
你像
You're like me but...
戴着帽子的我
with a hat.
他确实戴着帽子
He does wear a hat.
你们看起来都和我一样
You all look like me.
我们去大吃一顿吧 庆祝我儿子回来了
Let's feast in my son's honor.
- 这是什么 - 熊猫不用走的 我们滚吧
- What the...? - Pandas don't walk! We roll!
你有见过这么可笑的人吗
How you ever seen anyone look so ridiculous?
阿宝 你在干什么 阿宝
Po, what are you doing? Po?
你说得对 的确比走路强多了
You're right. That is better than walking.
- 对 - 好东西
- Yeah. - That's nice stuff.
吃点包子吧
Yeah, have some dumplings.
哪有不会滚的熊猫呀
What kind of panda doesn't know how to roll?
在当熊猫这方面 我还是新人
Well, I'm kinda new at this whole being a panda thing.
你是什么品种的熊猫啊 你脖子好搞笑
Hey, what kind of panda are you? You have a funny neck.
我根本不是熊猫
I'm not a panda at all.
那是什么 那个呢 这个呢
What's that? What's that? What's that?
我的帽子 我的嘴 我的翅膀 我的包子
My hat, My beak, My wing, My dumplings.
别再问问题了 坐好 小屁孩
No more questions. Go away, kid.
- 儿子 给你 我给你带了筷子 - 谢谢你 老爸
- Here, son, I packed your chopsticks. - Thanks, dad.
- 怎么了 - 那是干什么用的
- What? - What are those for?
这个 这是筷子 用来夹包子
These? These are chopsticks. They're for picking up dumplings.
你是说 你只一口一个包子
You mean you only eat one at a time?
我就知道我在吃方面潜力无限
I knew I wasn't eating up to my potential.
我是美美
I am Mei Mei.
她真是花容月貌 美若天仙
She's amazing. She's so beautiful.
嘴真甜 阿宝 不过留着些好话
That's sweet, Po, but please try to save all
等我表演完了再夸
other compliments until after the performance.
我 不 我没说
Me? No, I didn't say...
别说话 表演完再夸
Shut it. After the performance.
还没开始吗
Has it started yet?
全天下最棒的彩带舞者
Best ribbon dancer in the world.
- 至少她是这么说的 - 看 看
- At least that's what she says. - Look away, look away.
不 你做不到 对吧
No, you can't. Can you?
老爸 为啥她一直那样盯着我看啊
Dad, why does she keep staring at me like that?
试着跟上姐的舞步
Try to keep up.
- 我真不知道怎么跳舞 - 你当然知道
- I don't really know how to dance. - Of course you do.
所有熊猫都会跳舞
All pandas dance.
- 我知道你在想什么 - 真的吗
- I know what you're thinking. - You do?
一只熊猫怎么能如此貌美呢
How can one panda be so beautiful?
- 哇哦 - 送我的 谢谢
- Whoa! - For me? Fine.
- 帮帮我 老爸 - 哦 不 你得自己来
- Help me, dads. - Yeah, no. You're on your own.
跳的不错 儿子
You're doing great, son.
该你了
Your turn.
把他带回家吧
Bring it home!
没关系 你会掌握窍门的
Don't worry, you'll get the hang of it.
我要学的东西多着呢
I have so much to learn.
追踪之翼
Wings of surveillance.
- 你说那个干嘛 - 说什么
- Why do you do that? - Do what?
在做的事情前面加上"之翼"什么的
Just because you say "Wings of"...
可不代表你的做法有多特别
before something it doesn't mean that you're doing a special move.
就好像我说"强力之刃"或者
It's like me saying, "Antenna of power" or...
"三明治之喉"那样
"Thorax of making sandwiches"
- 反对之翼 - 哇 那里
- Wings of disagreement. - Whoa, there.
熊大师 鸡大师 鳄鱼大师 你们在这干嘛呢
Master Bear, Master Chicken, Master Croc, what are you doing out here?
翡翠军团袭击了我们的村庄 我们追到了这里
Jade creatures attacked our villages. We've tracked them here.
停下
Stop.
他们一定在里面
They must be in there.
师父让我们坚决
Master Shifu strongly advised us....
- 不要和他交手 - 我们必须进去
- ...not to engage. - We got to get in there.
- 但师父说 - 你害怕了吗
- But Master Shifu said... - You're seriously afraid?
连鸡大师都进去了 他可是只鸡啊
Even Master Chicken's going in there and he's a chicken.
就这么定了 我要进去了
That's it, I'm going in.
螳螂 我们有命令在身 不能
Mantis, we have orders not to...
他们需要帮忙 快点 我从上方攻击 你从下面
They need our help. Come on. I'll go high, you go low.
别 等等
No, wait.
难道还怕只虫子
Fear the bug.
看着 你个小
Alright, you little...!
- 坚持住 伙计 我来了 - "强力之刃"
- Hold on, buddy. I'm coming. - "Antenna of power"
- 啊 怎么不管用 - 螳螂
- Ah, it didn't work! - Mantis!
螳螂
Mantis?
你的气很强 和你的朋友一样 那个小虫子
Your chi is strong, just like your friend, the bug.
啊 螳螂
Huh? Mantis.
别担心 小鸟儿 我会让你的真气派上好用场的
Don't worry, little birdie. I'll put your chi to good use.
我将毁掉翡翠宫和它里面的每一个人
Destroying the Jade palace and everyone in it.
不可能
No.
悔过 之翼
Wings of...regret.
哦 没错 熊猫训练的第一天
Oh yeah, first day of panda training.
好了 花儿 我会让你开放的
Alright flower, I'm gonna make you bloom.
老爸 老爸
Dad, dad.
干嘛 干嘛 什么事啊
What? What? What is it?
我准备好迎接第一天的熊猫训练啦
I'm ready for my first day of panda training.
什么
What?
就是学着怎么做只熊猫啊 一位气功大师 拯救世界
You know, learn to be a panda, Master chi, save the world.
熊猫要睡到午后才起床的
Pandas sleep till past noon.
所以第一课就是回被窝接着睡
So lesson number one is go back to bed.
好吧
Of course.
没听说过这玩意这么简单
Nobody said this was gonna be easy.
- 我睡过头了吗 - 哈哈 当然
- Did I oversleep? - Ha, ha! You sure did.
好样的
Yes!
对了 孩子们 给他示范一下
Yeah, show him kids.
你能这样吗 能这样吗
Can you do this? Can you do that?
- 这样呢 还有这样呢 - 嘿
- How about this? How about that? - Hey?
我做的对吗 这样好不好呢
Am I doing it? Is this good?
就这样 我会了
Here we go. I got it!
- 熊猫奶奶 小心头顶 - 噢
- Grandma panda, heads up. - Ow.
- 噢 - 我们还是打滚吧
- Oh. - We better roll.
阿宝 午饭时间到了
Po, lunchtime.
阿宝 你要顺其自然的滚才行啊
Po. You gotta let the hill tell you where to roll.
菜鸟都这样
Rookie mistake.
点点 心心 让他看看我们是如何上山的吧
Dim, Sum, let's show him how we go uphill.
- 太帅了 - 吃点心啦 噢
- It's beautiful. - Snack time. Oh.
- 阿宝 你会飞了 - 全速前进
- Po, you can fly? - I'm coming in hot!
那就等凉了再吃吧
Get them while they're cold.
你们在这干嘛 那些是给阿宝的
What are you doing there? That food is for Po.
下锅咯
Throw it in.
抱抱 抱抱 就这样
There, there, that's it.
- 感到放松了吗 - 嗯 是的
- Feeling relaxed? - Yeah, really.
- 只要顺其自然就好 - 懂了
- Just let yourself fall into it. - Got it.
我没事 我只是
I'm fine. I just...
这就对了 都吐出来就好了
There we go. Just let it all out.
这才是我的好孩子
That's my boy.
出去
Get out of there!
我的面条 别动我的面条
My noodles. Leave my noodles alone.
- 讨厌 阿宝 真讨厌 - 我也要抱抱
- Subtle, Po. Very subtle. - Let me get some of that.
别吃我的帽子
And leave my hat alone.
- 我们爱吃面条 - 噢 多像阿宝小的时候啊
- We love noodles! - Oh, just like my Po.
你们看什么呢
What are you guys looking at?
我们就是这样滚的 发炮
That's how we roll. Cannonball.
哈哈 来了
Hoo-hoo. Yeah!
妈妈 看呀
Mom, look it.
这次怎么样
How was that?
- 现在你再试一次 但别太用力 - 好的
- Now you try again but don't try so hard. - Okay, Okay.
好多了
Much better.
- 谢谢你 老爸 - 谢什么
- Thanks, dad. - For what?
你懂的 就是 告诉我做一只熊猫
You know, just for you know, showing me what it feels like...
是怎样的感觉
to be a panda.
那么你究竟认为我什么时候能准备充分呢
So when do you think I'll be ready?
准备充分
Ready?
就是学习怎样掌握气功呀
You know, to learn how to master chi.
很快 很快就可以了
Soon, real soon.
来吧 我想给你看点别的 跟我来
Come on. I wanna show you something else. Come on
真不好意思 这里乱七八糟的 我这很少有来访者
Sorry about the mess, I don't usually get visitors.
这是我妈妈么
Is this my mom?
我在你百日的时候完成了这幅画像
I had this done on your one hundredth day.
你妈妈根本没法让你安静下来
Your mama couldn't hold you still.
你差点把这张纸给吃了
You nearly eat the paper.
- 真的 - 她什么样
- It's true. - What was she like?
她简直完美
She was the total package.
聪明 美丽
Smart, beautiful.
食量巨大
Tremendous appetite.
她是我一生的挚爱
She was the love of my life.
然后 就在我觉得人生达到最美满的时候
And then, just when I thought I couldn't get any luckier.
你降临了 我的小莲花
Along you came, my Little Lotus.
那时我真的拥有了世界的全部
I really had it all.
直到那一天
Until that one moment...
当我
When I...
又失去了一切
lost everything.
老爸 你再也不用担心会失去我了 好吗
Dad, you don't have to worry about losing me ever again, Okay?
让我也来抱抱
Let me get some of that.
从东部来的消息
It's from the eastern province.
蜥蜴大师 红牛大师 猎鹰大师 他们全部
Master Lizard, Master Ox, Master Eagle, all of them.
隔海相望的每一座村庄 天底下每一位功夫大师
In every village from the sea to here. Every Master in china...
- 都不见了 - 也许他们都去参加某个宴会了呢
- ...has vanished. - Maybe they are all at a party?
- 灵猴 - 我也没被邀请呀
- Monkey. - I didn't get invited either.
是天煞吸走了他们的真气
Kai has taken their chi.
现在只有我们能阻止他了 而龟仙人留下的真传
We are all that stand between him and the knowledge Oogway left
只有靠我们来守护了
in our care.
- 村民们都疏散了吗 - 全部疏散了 师父
- The villagers, evacuated? - Done, Master.
- 仙鹤和螳螂呢 - 还没有消息
- Crane? Mantis? - Still nothing.
啊 等等 他们回来了
Huh! Wait, it's them!
不
No!
天煞
Kai.
好极了 你们就这点本事
Nice, very tacky.
你胆敢踏上这片土地
How dare you set foot on these grounds!
看看你们这群可怜的傻瓜吧
Look at your pathetic fools.
只知道在乌龟的脚下卑躬屈膝
Groveling at the feet of Oogway the magnificent.
你根本不配提及他的名字
You are not fit to speak his name.
我不配吗 小猫咪
I am not fit, little kitten?
我曾与他并肩作战 我待他如同手足
I fought by his side. I loved him like a brother.
而他却背叛了我
And he betrayed me.
好吧 那我就毁了他所创造的一切
Well, now I will destroy everything he has created.
上
Go!
小猫咪让你感觉如何
How's that for a little kitten?
我不会让你毁了龟仙人的记忆
I will not let you destroy Oogway's memory.
为什么不呢 他可是毁掉了我的
Why not? He destroyed mine.
螳螂 是我啊 你的好哥们
Mantis, it is me, your bestie.
对不起 娇虎 抱歉 抱歉 抱歉
Sorry Tigress. Sorry, sorry, sorry.
抱歉
Sorry.
- 师父 - 把他们都给我带来
- Shifu. - Bring them to me.
- 不行 你必须去找阿宝 - 师父 求你
- No! You must warn Po. - Master please.
让我给你见识 什么才叫真正的气功吧 兄弟
I will show you the true power of chi, brother.
不
No.
龟仙人 原谅我
Oogway, forgive me.
嗯 乌龟 你想说什么 你原谅他了吗
Hmm, what do you say Oogway? Do you forgive him?
你也许能毁掉翡翠宫
You may have destroyed the Jade palace.
但你永远不会得逞的
but you will never succeed.
总会有人能阻止你的
There will always be someone to stop you.
谁 那只熊猫 他的真气很强
Who? The panda? His chi is strong but
但那还远远不够
it won't be enough.
- 他会落得和你一样的下场 - 不可能
- He will meet the same fate as you. - No.
并且那个村子里每一只熊猫都会如此
And so will every panda in that village.
会的
Yes!
阿宝 我希望你准备好了
Po, I hope you're ready.
跳舞吧 小莲花 跳舞呀
Dance Lotus, dance.
真是个帅小伙
He's so handsome.
- 你好 - 来个熊抱
- Hi. - That's a panda hug.
嗨
Hey.
阿宝
Po.
啊 娇虎
Huh! Tigress?
她是谁
Who's she?
那是谁
Who is that?
- 花娃娃 - 你怎么来了
- Baby stripey baby. - What are you doing here?
天煞袭击了山谷 他抓走了那里所有的功夫大师
Kai attacked the valley. He's taken every Master in china
包括师父他们 他们 全都走了 阿宝
including Shifu and the others. It's...it's all gone, Po.
- 一切 所有人 - 所有人
- Everything, everyone. - Everyone?
- 所有人 - 那我的面馆呢
- Everyone. - How's my restaurant?
我们一会再谈
We'll talk later.
而且 现在他正在来这里的路上
And now he's on his way here.
他是冲着你来的 阿宝 还有所有的熊猫
He's after you, Po. He's after all pandas.
- 我们还有多长时间 - 不多了
- How long do we have? - Not long.
快告诉我你已经学会气功了
Please tell me you've mastered chi.
- 这里 抱着孩子 - 老爸 老爸
- Here, take the baby. - Dad, dad.
好了 这孩子是谁家的
Okay, who belongs to this one?
你现在必须教我气功的秘诀了
You need to teach me the secret chi technique now.
不 不行 恐怕你还没准备好
No, no. I'm afraid you need more time.
大家快收拾好行装
Everyone, go get your things.
- 我替你拿着 - 我没时间了 我得立刻学才行
- Let me hand you that. - I don't have more time. I need to learn it now.
对不起 你还没准备好
Sorry, you're not ready.
- 好了 把所有东西都装好 - 我准备好了
- Okay, pack everything. - I am ready!
还不够
Not quite.
究竟是什么意思啊 你说的每一件事我都照做了
What are you talking about? I've done everything you've asked.
我学会了了打瞌睡 在吊床上睡觉 泡热水澡
I Mastered napping, sleeping in hammocks, the hot tubs.
我完全学会如何做一只熊猫了
I am totally in one with my panda parts
为什么你现在还是不能教我
Now, why won't you show me?
因为我根本就不会
Because I don't know it!
你说什么
You what?
我不会气功 明白吗
I don't know it, Okay?
没有人会 或许曾经有人会 但是
No one does. Maybe we used to but...
- 早已失传了 - 你骗了我
- But not anymore. - You lied?
没有 我
No, I...
是的
Yes.
为什么
Why?
为了救你的命
To save your life.
我听说有个耍刀的疯子到处找你
I find out some blade-swinging maniac is coming for you.
我还能做什么
What am I supposed to do?
- 袖手旁观吗 - 当然 我是神龙大侠啊
- Just...just let that happen? - Yes, I'm the Dragon Warrior!
对付那些疯子 那是我的职责
Facing maniacs, that's my job.
但因为你 我让整个村庄都失去庇护
But because of you, I left the valley unprotected.
我让我的朋友失去保护
I left my friends unprotected.
而现在他们都 他们都
And now they're all...they're all...
你留下来也会和他们一样被抓走的
And you would have been, too.
我失去过你一次 我不能再次失去你了
I lost you once. I am not going to lose you again.
我不能
I can't.
你已经失去我了
You just did.
妈妈 抱着我
Mom, pick me.
阿宝 我担心死你了
Po, I'm so worried for you that
以至于一切如我所料都没能让我开心
I can't even enjoy being right about everything.
现在逃吧 逃吧 逃吧
Now run, run, run,
甩开你那小胖腿用最快速度逃吧
as fast as those chubby legs can go.
- 逃 现在已经无处可逃了 - 那你打算怎么办
- Run? There's nowhere to run. - What are you going to do?
我要留下 打倒那个混蛋
I'm gonna stay and fight that monster.
阿宝 他可能是个混蛋 但他到底还是你爸爸啊
Po, he may be a monster but he's still your father.
- 不是他 是天煞 - 啊 不要
- Not him, Kai. - Huh! No.
- 你饿吗 - 不 真的 不饿
- Hungry? - No, I... not really.
好吧 就吃一个吧
Well, maybe just one.
要知道 说谎的人不止你一个
You know, you weren't the only one who was lying.
我来到这里 不是因为我担心阿宝会挨饿
I didn't really come along because I was worried Po would go hungry.
- 我担心的是你 - 你担心我会挨饿
- I was worried about you. - Worried that I'd go hungry?
- 不 我担心你会把阿宝从我身边夺走 - 什么
- No, I was worried you'd steal Po from me. - I'd what?
我知道这想法很奇怪
I know. That was crazy.
但后来我意识到阿宝的人生出现了你
But I realized having you in Po's life
那并不是我的损失
doesn't mean less for me.
而是意味着阿宝得到的爱更多
It means more for Po.
喔
Oh.
不过 他的人生已经不要我了
Well. I'm not in his life.
- 再也不要我了 - 你儿子生你气了
- Not any more. - Your son got mad at you.
- 欢迎加入为人父母的行列 - 你不懂
- Welcome to parenthood. - You don't understand.
我骗了他 他再也不会原谅我了
I lied to him. He'll never forgive me.
我骗了他二十年啊
I lied to him for 20 years.
他一直以为他是从一颗蛋里孵出来的
He still thinks he came from an egg.
有时候我们所做的错事 往往是出于善意
Sometimes we do the wrong things for the right reasons.
听着 他很难过
Look, he's hurt.
也很迷茫 但他还是选择了拯救世界
He's confused and he still has to save the world.
现在正是他最需要我们的时候
He needs the both his dads.
- 这样没有用 - 会有用的
- This isn't going to work. - It has to.
- 你现在头脑不清醒 - 我很清醒
- You 're not thinking straight. - I am.
- 不是 - 是的
- You're not. - I am.
- 不 - 是的 我很好
- No. - Yes, I am.
我见过天煞 我知道他的本事如何
I've seen Kai. I've seen what he can do.
但他还没领略过我的本领
But he hasn't seen what I can do.
无须铁指扣
The Wuxi finger hold?
这是我的绝招
That's my best move.
我只需要找到天煞 捏住他的手指
I just have to get to Kai, grab his finger,
然后 走你 他就能滚回灵界
and then, Skadoosh. Back to the Spirit Realm.
他有一支翡翠军团
He has an army of jade warriors.
他们见过的一切他都能够感知
Everything they see he sees
所以你根本无法抓住他的把柄
so there's no sneaking up on him.
- 你没法近他身 - 这招会管用的
- You will never get close enough. - It's gonna work.
只有真正的气功大师才能够阻止他
He can only be stopped by a Master of chi.
哦 你跟师父的腔调一模一样
Oh, you sound just like Shifu with
气功 气功 气功 这个气 那个气 气 气 气 气 气
the chi chi chi. Chi this. Chi that. Chi chi chi chi chi.
我不是气功大师 好吗
I'm not a Master of chi. Okay?
我也不知道我是不是什么神龙大侠
I don't know if I'm the Dragon Warrior.
我甚至不知道我是不是只熊猫
I don't even know if I'm a panda.
我连我自己是谁都不知道
I don't know who I am.
你是对的
You're right.
我没办法阻止他和他的大军
There's no way I can stop him and his army.
除非你有一支你自己的军队
Unless you had an army of your own.
- 你 - 不仅仅是我
- You? - Not just me.
- 我们 - 我们所有人
- Us. - All of us.
这么多年之后我终于找到了我的儿子
I finally found my son after all these years.
就算世界末日也不能把我们分开
It's gonna take a lot more than the end of the world to keep us apart.
- 但你们都不会功夫啊 - 你可以教我们啊
- But you don't even know kung fu. - Then you will teach us.
什么 我教不了你功夫 我连娇虎都教不了
What? I can't teach you kung fu. I couldn't even teach Tigress.
而她还是功夫高手
And she already knows kung fu!
阿宝 我知道我现在是你最不愿信任的人
Po, I know I'm the last guy you wanna trust right now.
但你必须相信我 我们能做到
But you gotta believe me. We can do this.
我们可以学会功夫 我们可以变成你那样
We can learn kung fu. We can be just like you.
你刚说什么
What did you just say?
- 呃 我们能做到 - 不是
- Uh... We can do this? - No.
- 我们可以学会功夫 - 后面一句
- We can learn kung fu? - After that.
呃 我 我们可以变成你那样
Uh... I... We can be just like you?
- 没错 - 我们真能做到吗
- Yes! - We can?
不 你们做不到
No, you can't!
但你们不必像我
But you don't have to be.
师父当初就是这个意思 我不必把你们变成另一个我
That's what Shifu meant. I don't have to turn you into me.
我要做的是激发你们自身的潜能
I have to turn you into you!
这根本说不通啊
That doesn't make any sense.
我知道
I know!
- 谢谢爸爸们 - 不用谢
- Thanks, dads. - You're welcome?
我要做件自己从未想过能办到的事
I'm gonna do something I never thought I'd be able to do.
我要教功夫
I'm gonna teach kung fu.
伙计们 展现出自己最好的水平就是你们真正的优势
You guys, your real strength comes from being the best you you can be.
那么 你是谁 你擅长什么
So, who are you? What are you good at?
你热衷什么 何为你的个人特色
What do you love? What makes you you?
很好 很好 接着踢
Yes, good. Good, again.
很好 继续
Good, again.
很好 非常好 继续
Good, good, good, again.
- 什么 - 花娃娃 花娃娃
- Huh? - Stripey baby, stripey baby
快点 再快点 挥动这些绸带
Faster, faster. Roll those ribbons!
抱紧这根木头 就像是你平生最后一次
Hug that log, you. Hug that log
拥抱它一样 把这当作是最后的道别
like it's the last time you're ever gonna hug it. Goodbye forever.
高点 这次稍微偏向左边 你能行的
Higher, and a little more to the left this time. You can do it.
我不想看到任何一个包子接触地面
I don't wanna see any of these hit the ground.
等等 给花娃娃留点
Wait, wait, save Stripy Baby some.
很好 试试这个
Good, try it with this.
现在 试试这些
Now try it with these.
很好 试试这个
Good, now try it with these.
噢
Oh.
- 啊 - 噢
- Ow. - Oooh.
他们准备好了
They are ready.
娃娃 他他他
Baby, he he he.
什么
What?
注意听了 因为我不可能重复讲十多遍
Okay pay attention cause I'm not gonna go over this ten more times.
村子的唯一入口在这
The only entrance to the village is here.
包子小分队守在这里 饼干小分队守在这里
The dumpling squadron will take position here while the cookie squadron will take position here.
那么当我发令后 这两个队就
Now, on my signal, the two squadrons will...
好吧 面条小分队要
Alright, Okay. The noodle squadron will...
好吧 总而言之 应该记住的重点是
Alright. Okay, anyway,the important thing to
这就是那个位置
remember is that this is the spot where...
好吧 我早猜到会是这样 你们记住一件事就好
Okay, I saw that coming. If you only remember one thing,
分散那群翡翠之尸的注意力 直到我与天煞的距离
it's just distract the jombies until I get close enough to put a
近到能使用无须铁指扣 明白了吗
Wuxi finger hold on Kai. You got it?
- 明白 - 明白
- Yeah! - Yeah!
大家都把手放上来
Pandas on three.
数到三喊加油 一 二 三 伙计们
One, two, three panda, you guys...
算了 我下次再教你们那个
Never mind. I'll teach you that later.
我真希望自己有教过你这个 儿子
I... I wish I could have taught you this, son.
没关系的 爸爸 我
It's okay, dad. I'm...
他来了
He's here.
哇
Whhhhooooaaa!
这才是我所说的华丽出场嘛
That's what I call a dramatic entrance.
哈哈 你肯定就是神龙大侠了
Haha, you must be the Dragon Warrior.
那你肯定是天煞吧
And you must be Kai.
复仇之兽 寡妇制造者
Beast of vengeance, maker of widows.
没错 终于有人认识我了
Yes, finally.
谢谢 我差点都想饶你一命了
Thank you, almost makes me wanna spare your life.
噢 你想饶我一命
Oh, you wanna spare me?
你能别废话了吗 开始吧
How about you spare me the chitchat, alright? Let's do this.
我要把你和其他所有熊猫的气都夺
I'm going to take your chi then the chi of every panda in the...
- 噢 又是废话 - 都夺
- Oh, chitchat. - in this...
- 怎么这么啰嗦啊 - 夺
- Chitty chitty chat chat chat chat chat - in...
- 夺走 - 废话连篇
- in the... - Chitchat.
噢 你这胖小子
Oh, you pudgy little...
包围他们
Round them all up.
噢不 你们真的都变绿了
Oh no, it's true. You guys have all been turned green.
除了你 螳螂 你本来就是绿色的
Except for you, Mantis, you were already green.
- 现在动手吗 - 等信号
- Now? - Wait for the signal.
哈
HAA!
开打啦
Here we go!
噢
Ooo.
包子小分队
Dumpling squad!
- 准备好了吗 - 冲啊
- Ready? - Go time.
- 肚子 - 锣
- Belly... - Gong...
没开玩笑吧
Seriously?
- 耶 - 我们成功了
- Yeah! - We did it!
- 哇 - 耶
- Woo hoo hoo. - Yeah!
对不起 仙鹤
Sorry, Crane.
春卷特攻队 送外卖咯
Spring roll squad. Time for some takeout.
哟 这呢 翡翠之尸
Yoo hoo. Over here, Mr. jombie.
我也不认识你
I don't know who you are either.
面条小分队
Noodle squad.
准备好与危险共舞吧
Get ready to dance with danger.
哇
Waaaaa!
噢 干得好
Oooh. Sweet.
- 花娃娃 - 啊
- Stripey baby - Huh!
- 揍他 - 你个坏蛋
- Do it. - You're mean.
开火
Fire.
小心鞭炮
Fire in the hole.
啊
Aww!
帅
Yes.
好样的 孩子们 干得好
All right, kids! You got it, guys.
噢不 是师父
Oh no, Master Shifu.
我不能打师父啊
I can't hit Shifu.
- 我能 - 我也能
- I can. - And, so can I.
- 双爸合璧 - 双爸合璧
- Double dad defense. - Double dad defense.
- 左边 爸爸 - 右边 爸爸
- Left, dad. - Right, dad.
谢谢爸
Thanks dad.
也谢谢你 爸爸
Back at you, dad.
儿子 有我们在呢
We've got this, son.
加油爸爸们
Ho ho. Go, dads!
耶
Yeah.
耶 哈哈
Yeah! Ha ha!
- 我们做到了 - 停 停 够了
- We got them now. - Stop, stop, enough.
住手
Stop.
我们来做个了结吧
Let's finish this.
- 不愧是我们的儿子 - 不愧是我们的儿子
- That's our boy! - That's our boy!
抱歉 兄弟 得把你打回灵界了
Sorry, buddy. Gotta send you back to the Spirit Realm.
走你
Skadoosh.
好吧 没成功
Okay, that didn't work.
我再试一次 走你
Let me try one more time. Skadoosh.
走你 走你 走你 怎么搞的
Skadoosh, skadoosh, skadoosh. What the?
等等 起作用了
Hold on, wait. It's working.
不 不
No. Nooo!
不 没用
No, it's not.
这小把戏是乌龟教给你的吗
Did Oogway teach you that little trick?
真可惜 这招只对凡人管用
Too bad. It only works on mortals.
而我是灵界煞星
And I am a spirit warrior.
回来吧
Come!
儿子
Son!
阿宝
Po!
看来我错了 真抱歉 快跑 跑啊
I was wrong. I'm sorry. Run. Run!
乌龟 这难道就是命中注定要阻止我的人吗
So, Oogway, this was the one destined to stop me?
我将把他和其余所有人的气收入囊中
I will have his chi and then all of theirs.
而你 哈哈哈哈
And you... Hehahahaha.
你真的以为你能把我打回灵界吗
You really thought you can send me back to the Spirit Realm?
你只不过是个愚蠢的凡人
You are just a stupid mortal.
只对凡人有效
It only works on mortals.
你说的对 我没法打你回那里
You're right. I can't send you there.
但我可以带你过去 那是什么
But I can take you there. What's that?
噢 什么
Oh. What?
- 阿宝 - 儿子
- Po. - Son!
走你
Skadoosh.
- 儿子 - 儿子
- Son! - Son!
不
No!
- 啊 - 啊
- Aw! - Aw!
怎么回事 阿宝去哪了
What... What happened? Where is Po?
他带走了天煞 也救了我们
He took Kai away. He saved us.
不
No.
他救了我们 那谁来救他
He saved us but who's saving him?
哇 灵界 管用了啊
Whoa, the Spirit Realm! It worked!
别骑我 你
Get off me, you...
你带我回来了
You brought me back?
别怪我 我试过在凡界解决这事 但没成功啊
Don't blame me. I tried to finish this in the regular realm.
那我们在这了结吧
And we'll finish it here.
加油啊 儿子 跟他拼了
Come on, son. Fight.
我们得帮他
We have to help him.
好了 大家都围过来 就是这样 靠近点
Okay, everyone gather around. That's it. Come in close.
加油 我们能办到的
Come on. We can do this.
阿宝 是你教会了我们要做真实的自己
Po, you taught us who we were meant to be.
父亲
A father.
- 朋友 - 踢包小将
- A friend. - A dumpling kicker.
- 致命老奶奶 - 拥抱者
- A lethal fighting machine. - A hugger.
双截棍女侠
A nunchuck chick.
花娃娃
Stripey baby.
家人
A family.
真棒
Sweet.
啊
Ah!
你是谁
Who are you?
我也有同样的困惑
I've been asking the same question.
我是熊猫之子
Am I the son of a panda?
还是大鹅之子 我是学生
The son of a goose? A student?
还是老师
A teacher?
结果我发现 我四者皆是
Turns out, I'm all of them.
我就是神龙大侠
I am the Dragon Warrior.
懂吗 看到这条巨龙了吗
Get it? See the giant dragon?
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha!
准备好感受这惊天巨雷吧
Get ready to feel the thunder.
太棒了
This is awesome!
吼吼 哈哈
Ho ho ho ho. Ha ha!
哇哦
Waa hoo!
啊哦
Oh oh.
肚皮锣
Belly gong.
神龙摆尾
Butt slap.
要不先吃点午餐吧 我饿死了
Perhaps a bit of lunch cause I'm starving.
不错
Mmm.
接招吧
Let's do this!
小心噢
Heads up.
我花了五百年才夺走乌龟的气
It took me 500 years to take Oogway's chi.
为了夺走你的气 我愿意再花五百年
I will have yours if it takes me 500 more.
废话 废话 都是废话
Chtity chitty chat chat, chitchat.
你这么想要我的气 那就拿去吧
You want my chi so bad? Then take it.
好啊 力量归我了
Yes, the power is mine.
等等 不 太多了
Wait, no. It's too much.
太多了 不
That's too much. No.
不要
Noooo!
他去哪了
Where'd he go?
- 我们回来了 - 好朋友
- We're back. - Bestie.
我还是绿的 没用啊
I'm still green. It didn't work!
噢等等 这是我正常时的绿色
Oh wait, that's my normal green.
- 绿娃娃 - 我不是娃娃 不是娃娃
- Greeny baby. - Not a baby, not a baby!
我是令人畏惧的螳螂
Antenna of Fear.
阿宝呢
What about Po?
- 你看到阿宝了吗 - 没有 他不在这吗
- Have you seen Po? - No, he's not here?
阿宝 阿宝
Po? Po?
他怎么没回来
Why isn't he back?
- 神龙大侠 - 乌龟 哇
- Dragon warrior. - Oogway? Whoaaa.
我不敢相信
I can't believe it.
- 哇 你格外耀眼 - 你也是
- Whoa, you're extra shiny. - As are you.
是吧 简直是史上最好的披风
I know, right? It's like the best cape ever.
当我披着它奔跑时 看起来超酷的
When I run with it, then it looks really cool.
披风很适合你 你长大了
It suits you. You've grown.
是啊 我不能再吃熊猫大餐了
Yeah, I gotta lay off the panda buffet.
我是说你变成熟了
Grown up.
当我把消息传给你父亲时 我就期待你能变成这样
As I hoped you would when I sent the message to your father.
啊
Huh.
原来那条宇宙消息是你发的啊 哇
You sent the universe mail? Whoa!
是的 因为宇宙需要你
Yes, because the universe needed you.
我吗
Me?
你终于变成了自己命中注定的样子
You finally became the panda you were always meant to be.
但你怎么知道我能做到
But how'd you know I could?
我们初次见面的那一天
On the first day we met...
我看到了功夫的未来
I saw the future of kung fu.
也看到了过往
And the past.
我看到了那只能将两者合二为一的熊猫
I saw the panda who could unite them both.
这就是我选你的原因 阿宝
That is why I chose you, Po.
你结合了阴阳两极
Both sides of the Yin and Yang.
也是我真正的继承者
And my true successor.
我吗 我 我可不能收下
Me? I can't... I can't take that.
拿着吧
Just take it.
我还有根更大的
I have a bigger one.
我是说 你悟性已经那么高了 而我只是
I mean, you're enlightening and everything. I'm just...
噢
Huh. Ooooh.
- 真的吗 - 是的
- Really? - Yes.
那现在我们怎么办
Now, what do we do?
你说呢
Hmm, you tell me.
不 乌龟 别走啊
No, Oogway, don't go!
我哪都不会去 我住在这
I'm not going anywhere. I live here.
噢 对哦
Oh right.
必须要决定去留的是你
It's you who must decide whether to stay or go.
- 等等 我能回去吗 - 谁知道呢
- Wait, I can go back? - Who knows?
我从没试过
I've never tried.
哇
Wow!
阿宝
Po.
噢 你能飞了
Ohhh. You can fly.
爸 爸 爸爸们
Dad, Dad, Dads!
- 儿子 - 儿子
- Son. - Son.
你可别再消失在花瓣中了
Don't you go disappearing in petals ever again.
我们以为永远失去你了
We thought we lost you.
不 是你救了我 是大家救了我
No, you saved me. You all did.
大家都过来吧
Now come on over here.
拥抱一下
Hugs
师父
Master Shifu!
学生终于变为了真正的老师
The student has truly become the tea...
等等 你从哪拿到这个的
Wait, where did you get that?
噢这个啊 乌龟在灵界给我的
Oh this. Oogway gave it to me in the Spirit Realm.
噢 他当然会这么做了
Oh. Of course he did.
我想我已经掌握了气功
I think I mastered chi.
噢 你当然能了
Oh. Of course you did.
你可以教我吗
Can you teach me?
准备好
Ready!
金猴 帮帮我
Monkey, help me.
绿娃娃
Greeny baby.
把她给我弄走
Get her off me!
噢 你好啊
Mmm. Hello.
走你
Skadoosh.
熊猫哮喘综合征
Panda asthma.